Guide to the Time Inc. Money Editorial Records: Managing Editor Marshall Loeb Files 1981-1986 MS 3009-RG 11
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Money Editorial Records: Managing Editor Marshall Loeb Files
1981-1986
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 11
3 Linear feet in 3 records cartons
The Time Inc. Money Editorial Records: Managing Editor Marshall Loeb Files focus on public appearances made by Loeb while he was managing editor. The collection is primarily scripts and transcripts.
Historical Note
In the early 1970s, Time Inc.'s magazine development group noticed a trend. While many general interest magazines struggled to sell, special interest magazines were gaining wider popularity. To capitalize on this trend, the magazine development group explored developing more special interest magazines. Otto Fuerbringer, the editor of the magazine development department, looked at previously discarded proposals for single topic magazines. Among these proposals was Money, a personal finance magazine aimed at telling readers how to intelligently spend their income.
Money began market testing in 1972 and was officially launched in 1974. The first issue of the magazine featured cover stories about prescription drug prices, real estate tax shelters, and working wives. Money remained in production for almost 47 years. As of June 2019, the magazine ceased physical publication. As of October 2019, the Money website was still active and publishing new content.
Citations:
Kelly, Keith J. "Money Magazine Going out of Print Following Failed Sales Auction." New York Post. New York Post, April 18, 2019. https://nypost.com/2019/04/17/money-magazine-going-out-of-print-following-failed-sales-auction/.
Personnel and Organization: Department Head Lists. Time Inc. Reference Files (MS 3009-RG 3), New-York Historical Society.
Prendergast, Curtis, and Geoffrey Colvin. The World of Time Inc.: The Intimate History of a Changing Enterprise, Volume Three: 1960-1980. Edited by Robert Lubar. New York: Atheneum, 1986.
Biographical Note
Marshall Loeb was a writer and editor at Time Inc. between 1956 and 1994. Loeb previously worked as a foreign correspondent as well as a reporter for the St. Louis Globe-Democrat. In 1956, Time hired him as a writer and promoted him to the position of senior editor in 1966. Loeb remained a senior editor until 1979 when he began to work specifically as an economics editor. The following year Loeb moved from Time to become the managing editor at Money. As part of this new position, Loeb hosted "Your Dollars," a daily radio show on the CBS Radio Network, and wrote the syndicated column "Your Money." In 1986 he became the managing editor of Fortune where he remained until his retirement in 1994. While at his positions with Money and Fortune, Loeb also served as an editor with Time Inc.'s magazine development group.
Citation:
Personnel and Organization: Department Head Lists. Time Inc. Reference Files (MS 3009-RG 3), The New-York Historical Society.
Scope and Contents
The Time Inc. Money Editorial Records: Managing Editor Marshall Loeb Files focus on public appearances made by Loeb while he was managing editor. The record group is primarily scripts for the CBS radio show Your Dollars. Additionally, there are scripts for Loeb's television and radio appearances and transcripts of his speeches and roundtable discussions in which he was a participant along with notes and statistical reports.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Custodial History
Gift of Time Inc. 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers. Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library. Additional records about Money and information regarding its history can be found in the Time Inc. Subject Files (MS 3009-RG 1). The Time Inc. Magazine Development Records (MS 3009-RG 40) may also have related materials since Marshall Loeb worked in the magazine development at the same time that he serving as Money managing editor.
Corporation records; Corporations -- History.; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Organization files; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Journalists -- United States; Reporters and reporting -- United States; Loeb, Marshall; Time, inc.; Time, inc. -- History; Time, inc. -- Archives
- ABC Shoot, 1982-1983; 191273 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 1)
- British Investment in America, 1981 September 17; 191272 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 2)
- Champion Media Awards, 1982; 191271 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 3)
- Good Morning America, 1986; 191270 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 4)
- Good Morning America: Retirement Material, 1981-1985; 191269 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 5)
- Newsmark, undated; 191268 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 6)
- Your Dollars, 1985 August 26 - 1985 October 18; 191266 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 7)
- Your Dollars, 1985 July 1 - 1985 August 23; 191265 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 8)
- Your Dollars, 1985 April 22 - 1985 July 15; 191264 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 9-10)
- Your Dollars, 1985 April 1 - 1985 June 28; 191263 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 11)
- Your Dollars, 1985 January 21 - 1985 April 8; 191262 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 12-13)
- Your Dollars, 1984 December 31 - 1985 March 29; 191261 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 14)
- Your Dollars, 1984 January 2 - 1985 January 14; 191260 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 15)
- Your Dollars, 1984 October 1 - 1984 December 28; 191259 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 16)
- Your Dollars, 1984 July 2 - 1984 September 4; 191258 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 17)
- Your Dollars, 1984 April 16 - 1984 September 28; 191257 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 18)
- Your Dollars, 1983 January 3 - 1983 December 30; 191256 (Offsite-box 3703, Folder 19-20)
- Your Dollars, 1983 January 3 - 1983 December 30; 191255 (Offsite-box 3704, Folder 1)
- Your Dollars, 1982 May 31 - 1982 December 31; 191254 (Offsite-box 3704, Folder 2-4)
- Your Dollars, 1982 January 4 - 1982 May 28; 191253 (Offsite-box 3704, Folder 5-6)
- Your Dollars, 1982 January 4 - 1982 July 2; 191252 (Offsite-box 3704, Folder 7-11)
- Your Dollars, 1981 November 5 - 1982 May 28; 191251 (Offsite-box 3704, Folder 12-13)
- Your Dollars, 1981 July 1 - 1982 January 1; 191250 (Offsite-box 3704, Folder 14-15)
- Your Dollars, 1981 June 1 - 1981 December 27; 191249 (Offsite-box 3704, Folder 16-17)
- Your Dollars, 1981 June 1 - 1981 December 27; 191248 (Offsite-box 3705, Folder 1-2)
- Your Dollars, 1981 March 3 - 1981 June 30; 191247 (Offsite-box 3705, Folder 3-4)
- Your Dollars, 1981 January 5 - 1981 May 29 (Offsite-box 3705, Folder 5-8)
- Your Dollars: Audience Estimates, 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 3705, Folder 9)
- Your Dollars: CBS Ratings, 1983 (Offsite-box 3705, Folder 10)